Let's move on to the second half of the 30 to 2 ratio, giving breaths.
Rescue breaths provide the fresh oxygen that the blood needs to carry to the brain.
But before we begin, make sure you have a barrier device at your disposal.
Your instructor should have handed them out.
It could be a CPR pocket mask or a face shield.
We always use these when possible to protect both you and the patient.
We'll review the steps now as your instructor demonstrates.
Step one is to open the airway by performing a head tilt, chin lift.
Without opening the airway, air cannot reach the lungs
because the tongue often blocks the back of the throat in an unresponsive person.
To perform a head tilt, chin lift,
place one hand on the forehead to tilt the head back
and use the fingers of your other hand to lift the chin upward.
Step two is delivering the breaths.
While keeping the airway open,
use your thumb and index finger to pinch the nose completely closed.
Place your mask or mouth over theirs to create a tight seal and give two rescue breaths.
Each breath should last about one second.
The most important thing to watch for is visible chest rise.
You aren't trying to blow as hard as you can.
You just want to see that chest move up and down.
If you don't see the chest rise on the first try,
reposition the head and attempt a second breath.
If it still doesn't rise, don't keep trying.
Immediately go back to your 30 compressions
and try the breaths again after that set is done.
Remember, we must never interrupt our compressions for more than 10 seconds to give these breaths.